## **Curriculum Vitae**

# **Brandon Knight**

## **Contact Details:**

Address:	Courtyard Flat behind 232 Cobden View Road, Sheffield S10 1HT
Telephone:	07856038027
e-mail:	brandon_a_knight@hotmail.com

#### Personal Details:

Date of birth:	10 <sup>th</sup> March 1992
Marital status:	Single
Nationality	English
Driving Licence:	Provisional / I own a 125cc Motorcycle that I am eligible to drive

## **Summary:**

I was born in the UK but spent 4 years in Frederick Maryland USA from 2001-2005. To pursue my interests I have travelled independently from a young age throughout the UK and to and from America and am used to following timetables, resolving logistical problems, being flexible and adapting to my environment.

I see learning as a lifelong activity and am keen to learn new things. I have been exposed to a wide variety of experiences and am confident in communicating at all levels, keen to take on new challenges and not afraid to ask for guidance to ensure that objectives can be met within the required timescales. I am equally happy working independently or as part of a team and am quite comfortable taking leadership responsibility where that is appropriate.

For personal reasons I am relocating to Sheffield having rented out my flat in Ipswich and resigning from the job I have held for 8 years: I am therefore available for immediate employment.

## **Education:**

I was home educated from birth to getting my first full-time job as a result of which my formal qualifications are unrepresentative of my ability. In 2009 I passed City & Guilds Level 2 Certificates in Literacy & Numeracy (the equivalent of GCSE A-C grades) and I have passed the M150 Data, Computing and Information Course through the Open University.

My (home) education experience involved interacting with a wide cross section of people in a variety of settings, both informal and formal. I communicate well with people of all ages. I have been involved with fundraising for charities and got involved with setting up a resource centre for homeschooling families while we lived in America. I was also a Moderator on an established Home Education internet forum. There are a number of Home Education groups locally and through those I was involved in working with others to take part in a variety of workshops ranging from Science to History, participate in sporting events and producing Christmas pantomimes.

I attended 4 separate YHA "Do It 4 Real" camps which combine activities with team building and interpersonal skill development.

I spend a lot of time on the computer researching subjects of interest to me and I am efficient and accurate on a keyboard. I am familiar with Microsoft Office and a wide variety of other software including photo editing packages, Metalogic iMetal and Stockmaster. I am also familiar with MacOS systems.

## Work Experience:

## October 2011 to December 2019: IS&G Steel Stockholders Ltd, Claydon

I worked as a Sales Executive and over the years my responsibilities came to include: processing orders, managing customer accounts, stock procurement, pursuing potential new business, tech support, route planning, quality assurance, stock taking, handling cash and credit card payments and liaising with colleagues to assist where appropriate. I was also a keyholder for 6 years with responsibility for securing the offices.

The majority of the role was dealing with incoming and outgoing sales calls and emails, helping identify what products the client required and ensuring timely deliveries as well as any auxiliary services such as providing material certificates for QA and any additional accounting paperwork.

I was regularly responsible for covering various other admin positions and as such did everything from filing and organising manual and computer records to planning delivery routes, banking cash, reviewing CCTV and Dash Cam footage and maintaining stock levels for several specific ranges of our products.

I forged many strong working relationships with customers, suppliers and colleagues.

## October 2010 to November 2011: Store Twenty One, Stowmarket

I started as the store was going under a major refurbishment and rebrand from QS to Store Twenty One which involved a steep learning curve and required plenty of flexibility.

The main duties I was involved in were helping customers, handling sales and dealing with returns. I was also tasked with receiving stock, unpacking, hanging and displaying incoming materials.

#### August 2009 Plantsmans Preference, Diss

Assisting in the construction of a workshop and general nursery work. This was a limited time project contract.

## September 2008: Terrence Higgins Trust, London

I obtained a week's work experience at the Terrence Higgins Trust Head Office in London where was involved in reception and general office duties and learnt about their computer system. As a result of that I was offered two further weeks (paid) work to cover a sick leave absence at their Lighthouse West branch. There I dealt with incoming and outgoing mail, answering phones, preparing rooms and meeting with and directing visitors.

#### Interests:

I have a wide circle of friends locally, nationally and internationally and I enjoy keeping in contact and socialising with them all when possible. My main hobbies include dancing, cycling, reading, and playing video and board games.

## References:

Alan Leigh, Managing Director. Ryan Edwards, Sales Manager. Neil Smith, Works Manager.

IS&G Steel Stockholders Ltd IS&G Steel Stockholders Ltd IS&G Steel Stockholders Ltd Temple Wood, Stock Road Unit 32 Claydon Business Park Unit 32 Claydon Business Park West Hanningfield Gipping Road, Great Blakenham Gipping Road, Great Blakenham Chelmsford **Ipswich Ipswich** Essex Suffolk Suffolk CM2 8LL IP6 0NL IP6 0NL

01277 840 471 01473 830684 01473 830 684

alan.leigh@isg-steel.co.uk rvan.edwards@isg-steel.co.uk neil.smith@isg-steel.co.uk